{"sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584386215012", "topic": "Coronavirus Disease 2019 Basics", "typeOfInfo_4": {"answerText": "People can fight stigma and help, not hurt, others by providing social support. Counter stigma by learning and sharing facts. Communicating the facts that viruses do not target specific racial or ethnic groups and how COVID-19 actually spreads can help stop stigma.\n", "questionText": "\n\nHow can people help stop stigma related to COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 4, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 4, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_2": {"answerText": "On February 11, 2020 the World Health Organization <a href=\"https://twitter.com/DrTedros/status/1227297754499764230\">announced</a> an official name for the disease that is causing the 2019 novel coronavirus outbreak, first identified in Wuhan China. The new name of this disease is coronavirus disease 2019, abbreviated as COVID-19. In COVID-19, ‘CO’ stands for ‘corona,’ ‘VI’ for ‘virus,’ and ‘D’ for disease. Formerly, this disease was referred to as “2019 novel coronavirus” or “2019-nCoV”.\nThere are <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/index.html\">many types</a> of human coronaviruses including some that commonly cause mild upper-respiratory tract illnesses. COVID-19 is a new disease, caused be a novel (or new) coronavirus that has not previously been seen in humans. The name of this disease was selected following the World Health Organization (WHO) <a class=\"tp-link-policy\" data-domain-ext=\"int\" href=\"https://www.who.int/topics/infectious_diseases/naming-new-diseases/en/\">best practice<span class=\"sr-only\">external icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-external x16 fill-external\"></span></a>external icon for naming of new human infectious diseases.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhy is the disease being called coronavirus disease 2019, COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 2, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 2, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_3": {"answerText": "People in the U.S. may be worried or anxious about friends and relatives who are living in or visiting areas where COVID-19 is spreading. Some people are worried about the disease. Fear and anxiety can lead to social stigma, for example, towards Chinese or other Asian Americans or people who were in quarantine.\nStigma is discrimination against an identifiable group of people, a place, or a nation. Stigma is associated with a lack of knowledge about how COVID-19 spreads, a need to blame someone, fears about disease and death, and gossip that spreads rumors and myths.\nStigma hurts everyone by creating more fear or anger towards ordinary people instead of the disease that is causing the problem.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhy might someone blame or avoid individuals and groups (create stigma) because of COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 3, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 3, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "A novel coronavirus is a new coronavirus that has not been previously identified. The virus causing coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), is not the same as the <a href=\"/coronavirus/types.html\">coronaviruses that commonly circulate among humans</a> and cause mild illness, like the common cold.\nA diagnosis with coronavirus 229E, NL63, OC43, or HKU1 is not the same as a COVID-19 diagnosis. Patients with COVID-19 will be evaluated and cared for differently than patients with common coronavirus diagnosis.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat is a novel coronavirus?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"typeOfInfo_6": {"answerText": "It is not yet known whether weather and temperature impact the spread of COVID-19. Some other viruses, like the common cold and flu, spread more during cold weather months but that does not mean it is impossible to become sick with these viruses during other months.  At this time, it is not known whether the spread of COVID-19 will decrease when weather becomes warmer.  There is much more to learn about the transmissibility, severity, and other features associated with COVID-19 and investigations are ongoing.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWill warm weather stop the outbreak of COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 6, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 6, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584386553767", "topic": "How It Spreads", "typeOfInfo_7": {"answerText": "Community spread means people have been infected with the virus in an area, including some who are not sure how or where they became infected.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat is community spread?\n\n", "questionID": 7, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 7, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_4": {"answerText": "Quarantine means separating a person or group of people who have been exposed to a contagious disease but have not developed illness (symptoms) from others who have not been exposed, in order to prevent the possible spread of that disease. Quarantine is usually established for the incubation period of the communicable disease, which is the span of time during which people have developed illness after exposure. For COVID-19, the period of quarantine is 14 days from the last date of exposure, because 14 days is the longest incubation period seen for similar coronaviruses. Someone who has been released from COVID-19 quarantine is not considered a risk for spreading the virus to others because they have not developed illness during the incubation period.\n", "questionText": "\n\nCan someone who has been quarantined for COVID-19 spread the illness to others?\n\n", "questionID": 4, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 4, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_5": {"answerText": "Coronaviruses are generally thought to be spread from person-to-person through respiratory droplets. Currently there is no evidence to support transmission of COVID-19 associated with food. Before preparing or eating food it is important to always wash your hands with soap and water for 20 seconds for general food safety. Throughout the day wash your hands after blowing your nose, coughing or sneezing, or going to the bathroom.\nIt may be possible that a person can get COVID-19 by touching a surface or object that has the virus on it and then touching their own mouth, nose, or possibly their eyes, but this is not thought to be the main way the virus spreads.\nIn general, because of poor survivability of these coronaviruses on surfaces, there is likely very low risk of spread from food products or packaging that are shipped over a period of days or weeks at ambient, refrigerated, or frozen temperatures.\nLearn what is known about the <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prepare/transmission.html\">spread of COVID-19</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nCan the virus that causes COVID-19 be spread through food, including refrigerated or frozen food?\n\n", "questionID": 5, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 5, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_2": {"answerText": "This virus was first detected in Wuhan City, Hubei Province, China. The first infections were linked to a live animal market, but the virus is now spreading from person-to-person. It’s important to note that person-to-person spread can happen on a continuum. Some viruses are highly contagious (like measles), while other viruses are less so.\nThe virus that causes COVID-19 seems to be spreading easily and sustainably in the community (“community spread”) in <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prepare/transmission.html\">some affected geographic areas</a>. Community spread means people have been infected with the virus in an area, including some who are not sure how or where they became infected.\nLearn what is known about the <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/about/transmission.html\">spread of newly emerged coronaviruses</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nHow does the virus spread?\n\n", "questionID": 2, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 2, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_3": {"answerText": "The virus that causes COVID-19 is <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prepare/transmission.html\">spreading from person-to-person</a>. Someone who is actively sick with COVID-19 can spread the illness to others. That is why CDC recommends that these patients be isolated either in the hospital or at home (depending on how sick they are) until they are better and no longer pose a risk of infecting others.\nHow long someone is actively sick can vary so the decision on when to release someone from isolation is made on a case-by-case basis in consultation with doctors, infection prevention and control experts, and public health officials and involves considering specifics of each situation including disease severity, illness signs and symptoms, and results of laboratory testing for that patient.\nCurrent <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/disposition-hospitalized-patients.html\">CDC guidance for when it is OK to release someone from isolation</a> is made on a case by case basis and includes meeting all of the following requirements:\n\nThe patient is free from fever without the use of fever-reducing medications.\nThe patient is no longer showing symptoms, including cough.\nThe patient has tested negative on at least two consecutive respiratory specimens collected at least 24 hours apart.\n\nSomeone who has been released from isolation is not considered to pose a risk of infection to others.\n", "questionText": "\n\nCan someone who has had COVID-19 spread the illness to others?\n\n", "questionID": 3, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 3, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "Coronaviruses are a large family of viruses. Some cause illness in people, and others, such as canine and feline coronaviruses, only infect animals. Rarely, animal coronaviruses that infect animals have emerged to infect people and can spread between people. This is suspected to have occurred for the virus that causes COVID-19. Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) and Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) are two other examples of coronaviruses that originated from animals and then spread to people. More information about the source and spread of COVID-19 is available on the <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/cases-updates/summary.html\">Situation Summary: Source and Spread of the Virus</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat is the source of the virus?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"typeOfInfo_6": {"answerText": "If you are at higher risk of getting very sick from COVID-19, you should: stock up on supplies; take everyday precautions to keep space between yourself and others; when you go out in public, keep away from others who are sick; limit close contact and wash your hands often; and avoid crowds, cruise travel, and non-essential travel. If there is an outbreak in your community, stay home as much as possible. Watch for symptoms and emergency signs. If you get sick, stay home and call your doctor. More information on how to prepare, what to do if you get sick, and how communities and caregivers can support those at higher risk is available on <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/specific-groups/high-risk-complications.html\">People at Risk for Serious Illness from COVID-19. </a>\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat should people at higher risk of serious illness with COVID-19 do?\n\n", "questionID": 6, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 6, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584386949645", "topic": "How to Protect Yourself", "typeOfInfo_7": {"answerText": "CDC does not recommend that people who are well wear a facemask to protect themselves from respiratory illnesses, including COVID-19. You should only wear a mask if a healthcare professional recommends it. A facemask should be used by people who have COVID-19 and are showing symptoms. This is to protect others from the risk of getting infected. The use of facemasks also is crucial for <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/infection-control/control-recommendations.html\">health workers</a> and other <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/guidance-home-care.html\">people who are taking care of someone infected with COVID-19 in close settings</a> (at home or in a health care facility).\n", "questionText": "\n\nDoes CDC recommend the use of facemask to prevent COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 7, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 7, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_4": {"answerText": "There is information for <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/guidance-prevent-spread.html\">people who have had close contact</a> with a person confirmed to have, or being evaluated for, COVID-19 available online.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat should I do if I had close contact with someone who has COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 4, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 4, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_5": {"answerText": "Older adults and people of any age who have serious <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/specific-groups/high-risk-complications.html\">underlying medical conditions</a> may be at higher risk for more serious complications from COVID-19.  Based upon available information to date, those most at risk include\n\nPeople 65 years and older\nPeople who live in a nursing home or long-term care facility\nPeople of any age with the following underlying medical conditions, particularly those that are not well controlled\n\nChronic lung disease or asthma\nCongestive heart failure or coronary artery disease\nDiabetes\nNeurologic conditions that weaken ability to cough\nWeakened immune system\nChemotherapy or radiation for cancer (currently or in recent past)\nSickle cell anemia\nChronic kidney disease requiring dialysis\nCirrhosis of the liver\nLack of spleen or a spleen that doesn’t function correctly\nExtreme obesity (body mass index [BMI] >40)\n\n\nPeople who are pregnant\n\n", "questionText": "\n\nWho is at higher risk for serious illness from COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 5, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 5, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_2": {"answerText": "Yes. There have been cases of COVID-19 in the U.S. related to travel and through close contact. U.S. case counts are updated regularly Mondays through Fridays. See the <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/cases-updates/cases-in-us.html\">current U.S. case count of COVID-19</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nHas anyone in the United States gotten infected?\n\n", "questionID": 2, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 2, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_3": {"answerText": "Visit the <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prepare/prevention.html\">COVID-19 Prevention and Treatment</a> page to learn about how to protect yourself from respiratory illnesses, like COVID-19.\n", "questionText": "\n\nHow can I help protect myself?\n\n", "questionID": 3, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 3, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "This is a rapidly evolving situation and the <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/cases-updates/summary.html#risk-assessment\">risk assessment</a> may change daily. The latest updates are available on CDC’s Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) website.\n", "questionText": "\n\nAm I at risk for COVID-19 in the United States?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_8": {"answerText": "There is still a lot that is unknown about the newly emerged COVID-19 and how it spreads. Two other coronaviruses have emerged previously to cause severe illness in people (MERS-CoV and SARS-CoV). The virus that causes COVID-19 is more genetically related to SARS-CoV than MERS-CoV, but both are betacoronaviruses with their origins in bats. While we don’t know for sure that this virus will behave the same way as SARS-CoV and MERS-CoV, we can use the information gained from both of these earlier coronaviruses to guide us. In general, because of poor survivability of these coronaviruses on surfaces, there is likely very low risk of spread from products or packaging that are shipped over a period of days or weeks at ambient temperatures. Coronaviruses are generally thought to be spread most often by respiratory droplets. Currently there is no evidence to support transmission of COVID-19 associated with imported goods and there have not been any cases of COVID-19 in the United States associated with imported goods. Information will be provided on the <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-nCoV/index.html\">Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) website</a> as it becomes available.\n", "questionText": "\n\nAm I at risk for COVID-19 from a package or products shipping from China?\n\n", "questionID": 8, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 8, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_9": {"answerText": "<a id=\"donate-blood\"></a>In healthcare settings all across the United States, donated blood is a lifesaving, essential part of caring for patients. The need for donated blood is constant, and blood centers are open and in urgent need of donations. CDC encourages people who are well to continue to donate blood if they are able, even if they are practicing social distancing because of COVID-19. CDC is supporting blood centers by providing recommendations that will keep donors and staff safe. Examples of these recommendations include spacing donor chairs 6 feet apart, thoroughly adhering to environmental cleaning practices, and encouraging donors to make donation appointments ahead of time.\n", "questionText": "\n\nIs it okay for me to donate blood?\n\n", "questionID": 9, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 9, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584387482747", "topic": " COVID-19 and Children", "typeOfInfo_4": {"answerText": "No. If your child is healthy, there is no need for them to wear a facemask. Only people who have symptoms of illness or who are providing care to those who are ill should wear masks.\n", "questionText": "\n\nShould children wear masks?\n\n", "questionID": 4, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 4, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_2": {"answerText": "You can encourage your child to help stop the spread of COVID-19 by teaching them to do the same things everyone should do to stay healthy.\n\nClean hands often using soap and water or alcohol-based hand sanitizer\nAvoid people who are sick (coughing and sneezing)\nClean and disinfect high-touch surfaces daily in household common areas (e.g. tables, hard-backed chairs, doorknobs, light switches, remotes, handles, desks, toilets, sinks)\nLaunder items including washable plush toys as appropriate in accordance with the manufacturer’s instructions. If possible, launder items using the warmest appropriate water setting for the items and dry items completely. Dirty laundry from an ill person can be washed with other people’s items.\n\nYou can find additional information on preventing COVID-19 at <a href=\"/coronavirus/about/prevention.html\">Prevention for 2019 Novel Coronavirus</a> and at <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/community/index.html\">Preventing COVID-19 Spread in Communities</a>. Additional information on how COVID-19 is spread is available at <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/about/transmission.html\">How COVID-19 Spreads</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nHow can I protect my child from COVID-19 infection?\n\n", "questionID": 2, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 2, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_3": {"answerText": "No. The symptoms of COVID-19 are similar in children and adults. However, children with confirmed COVID-19 have generally presented with mild symptoms. Reported symptoms in children include cold-like symptoms, such as fever, runny nose, and cough. Vomiting and diarrhea have also been reported. It’s not known yet whether some children may be at higher risk for severe illness, for example, children with underlying medical conditions and special healthcare needs. There is much more to be learned about how the disease impacts children.\n", "questionText": "\n\nAre the symptoms of COVID-19 different in children than in adults?\n\n", "questionID": 3, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 3, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "Based on available evidence, children do not appear to be at higher risk for COVID-19 than adults. While some children and infants have been sick with COVID-19, adults make up most of the known cases to date. You can learn more about who is most at risk for health problems if they have COVID-19 infection on CDC’s current <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/summary.html#risk-assessment\">Risk Assessment</a> page.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat is the risk of my child becoming sick with COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"typeOfInfo_6": {"answerText": "Handwashing is one of the best ways to protect yourself and your family from getting sick. Wash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds, especially after blowing your nose, coughing, or sneezing; going to the bathroom; and before eating or preparing food. If soap and water are not readily available, use an alcohol-based hand sanitizer with at least 60% alcohol.\n", "questionText": "\n\nShould I use soap and water or a hand sanitizer to protect against COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 6, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 6, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584388242595", "topic": "Preparing Your Home for COVID-19", "typeOfInfo_7": {"answerText": "Clean and disinfect frequently touched surfaces such as tables, doorknobs, light switches, countertops, handles, desks, phones, keyboards, toilets, faucets, and sinks.  If surfaces are dirty, clean them using detergent or soap and water prior to disinfection. To disinfect, most common EPA-registered household disinfectants will work. See CDC’s recommendations <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/community/home/cleaning-disinfection.html\">for household cleaning and disinfection</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat cleaning products should I use to protect against COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 7, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 7, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_4": {"answerText": "Talk to the <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/specific-groups/guidance-for-schools.html\">school or facility</a> about their emergency operations plan. Understand the plan for continuing education and social services (such as student meal programs) during school dismissals. If your child attends a <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/community/colleges-universities.html\">college or university</a>, encourage them to learn about the school’s plan for a COVID-19 outbreak.\n", "questionText": "\n\nHow can I prepare in case my child’s school, childcare facility, or university is dismissed?\n\n", "questionID": 4, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 4, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_5": {"answerText": "Plan for potential changes at your workplace. Talk to your employer about their emergency operations plan, including sick-leave policies and telework options. <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/specific-groups/guidance-business-response.html\">Learn how businesses and employers can plan for and respond to COVID-19.</a>\n", "questionText": "\n\nHow can I prepare for COVID-19 at work?\n\n", "questionID": 5, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 5, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_2": {"answerText": "Practice everyday preventive actions to help reduce your risk of getting sick and remind everyone in your home to do the same. These actions are especially important for older adults and people who have severe chronic medical conditions:\n\nAvoid close contact with people who are sick.\nStay home when you are sick, except to get medical care.\nCover your coughs and sneezes with a tissue and throw the tissue in the trash.\nWash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds, especially after blowing your nose, coughing, or sneezing; going to the bathroom; and before eating or preparing food.\nIf soap and water are not readily available, use an alcohol-based hand sanitizer with at least 60% alcohol. Always wash hands with soap and water if hands are visibly dirty.\nClean and disinfect frequently touched surfaces and objects\n(e.g., tables, countertops, light switches, doorknobs, and cabinet handles).\n\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat steps can my family take to reduce our risk of getting COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 2, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 2, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_3": {"answerText": "Most people who get COVID-19 will be able to recover at home. <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/guidance-prevent-spread.html\">CDC has directions</a> for people who are recovering at home and their caregivers, including:\n\nStay home when you are sick, except to get medical care.\nIf you develop emergency warning signs for COVID-19 get medical attention immediately. In adults, emergency warning signs*:\n\n\n\n\nDifficulty breathing or shortness of breath\nPersistent pain or pressure in the chest\nNew confusion or inability to arouse\nBluish lips or face\n*This list is not all inclusive. Please consult your medical provider for any other symptom that is severe or concerning.\n\n\n\n\nUse a separate room and bathroom for sick household members (if possible).\nClean hands regularly by handwashing with soap and water or using an alcohol-based hand sanitizer with at least 60% alcohol.\nProvide your sick household member with clean disposable facemasks to wear at home, if available, to help prevent spreading COVID-19 to others.\n<a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/community/home/cleaning-disinfection.html\">Clean the sick room and bathroom</a>, as needed, to avoid unnecessary contact with the sick person.\nAvoid sharing personal items like utensils, food, and drinks.\n\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat should I do if someone in my house gets sick with COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 3, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 3, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "Create a household plan of action to help protect your health and the health of those you care about in the event of an outbreak of COVID-19 in your community:\n\nTalk with the people who need to be included in your plan, and discuss <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-nCoV/summary.html\">what to do if a COVID-19 outbreak occurs in your community</a>.\nPlan ways to care for those who might be at greater risk for serious complications, particularly <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/specific-groups/high-risk-complications.html\">older adults and those with severe chronic medical</a> conditions like heart, lung or kidney disease.\n\nMake sure they have access to several weeks of medications and supplies in case you need to stay home for prolonged periods of time.\n\n\nGet to know your neighbors and find out if your neighborhood has a website or social media page to stay connected.\nCreate a list of local organizations that you and your household can contact in the event you need access to information, healthcare services, support, and resources.\nCreate an emergency contact list of family, friends, neighbors, carpool drivers, health care providers, teachers, employers, the local public health department, and other community resources.\n\n", "questionText": "\n\nHow can my family and I prepare for COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584388857241", "topic": "In Case of an Outbreak in Your Community", "typeOfInfo_4": {"answerText": "Depending on the situation, public health officials may recommend community actions to reduce exposures to COVID-19, such as school dismissals. Read or watch local media sources that report school dismissals or and watch for communication from your child’s school. If schools are dismissed temporarily, discourage students and staff from gathering or socializing anywhere, like at a friend’s house, a favorite restaurant, or the local shopping mall.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWill schools be dismissed if there is an outbreak in my community?\n\n", "questionID": 4, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 4, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_5": {"answerText": "Follow the advice of your local health officials. Stay home if you can. Talk to your employer to discuss working from home, taking leave if you or someone in your household gets sick with <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/about/symptoms.html\">COVID-19 symptoms</a>, or if your child’s school is dismissed temporarily. Employers should be aware that more employees may need to stay at home to care for sick children or other sick family members than is usual in case of a community outbreak.\n", "questionText": "\n\nShould I go to work if there is an outbreak in my community?\n\n", "questionID": 5, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 5, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_2": {"answerText": "Outbreaks can be stressful for adults and children. Talk with your children about the outbreak, try to stay calm, and reassure them that they are safe. If appropriate, explain to them that most illness from COVID-19 seems to be mild. <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/childrenindisasters/helping-children-cope.html\">Children respond differently to stressful situations than adults</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nHow do I prepare my children in case of COVID-19 outbreak in our community?\n\n", "questionID": 2, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 2, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_3": {"answerText": "This is a new virus and we are still learning about it, but so far, there does not seem to be a lot of illness in children. Most illness, including serious illness, is happening in adults of working age and older adults. If there cases of COVID-19 that impact your child’s school, the school may dismiss students. Keep track of school dismissals in your community. Read or watch local media sources that report school dismissals. If schools are dismissed temporarily, use alternative childcare arrangements, if needed.\nIf your child/children become sick with COVID-19, notify their childcare facility or school. Talk with teachers about classroom assignments and activities they can do from home to keep up with their schoolwork.\nDiscourage children and teens from gathering in other public places while school is dismissed to help slow the spread of COVID-19 in the community.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat steps should parents take to protect children during a community outbreak?\n\n", "questionID": 3, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 3, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "During an outbreak, stay calm and put your preparedness plan to work. Follow the steps below:\n<a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/about/prevention-treatment.html\">Protect yourself and others</a>.\n\nStay home if you are sick. Keep away from people who are sick. Limit close contact with others as much as possible (about 6 feet).\n\nPut your household plan into action. \n\nStay informed about the local COVID-19 situation. Be aware of temporary school dismissals in your area, as this may affect your household’s daily routine.\n\n\nContinue practicing everyday preventive actions. Cover coughs and sneezes with a tissue and wash your hands often with soap and water for at least 20 seconds. If soap and water are not available, use a hand sanitizer that contains 60% alcohol. Clean frequently touched surfaces and objects daily using a regular household detergent and water.\nNotify your workplace as soon as possible if your regular work schedule changes. Ask to work from home or take leave if you or someone in your household gets sick with <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/about/symptoms.html\">COVID-19 symptoms</a>, or if your child’s school is dismissed temporarily. <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/specific-groups/guidance-business-response.html\">Learn how businesses and employers can plan for and respond to COVID-19.</a>\nStay in touch with others by phone or email. If you have a chronic medical condition and live alone, ask family, friends, and health care providers to check on you during an outbreak. Stay in touch with family and friends, especially those at increased risk of developing severe illness, such as older adults and people with severe chronic medical conditions.\n\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat should I do if there is an outbreak in my community?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584389201096", "topic": "Symptoms & Testing", "typeOfInfo_4": {"answerText": "People in the U.S. may be worried or anxious about friends and relatives who are living in or visiting areas where COVID-19 is spreading. Some people are worried about the disease. Fear and anxiety can lead to social stigma, for example, towards Chinese or other Asian Americans or people who were in quarantine.\nStigma is discrimination against an identifiable group of people, a place, or a nation. Stigma is associated with a lack of knowledge about how COVID-19 spreads, a need to blame someone, fears about disease and death, and gossip that spreads rumors and myths.\nStigma hurts everyone by creating more fear or anger towards ordinary people instead of the disease that is causing the problem.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhy might someone blame or avoid individuals and groups (create stigma) because of COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 4, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 4, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_5": {"answerText": "People can fight stigma and help, not hurt, others by providing social support. Counter stigma by learning and sharing facts. Communicating the facts that viruses do not target specific racial or ethnic groups and how COVID-19 actually spreads can help stop stigma.\n", "questionText": "\n\nHow can people help stop stigma related to COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 5, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 5, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_2": {"answerText": "If you develop symptoms such as fever, cough, and/or difficulty breathing, and have been in close contact with a person known to have COVID-19 or have recently traveled from an area with <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prepare/transmission.html\">ongoing spread of COVID-19</a>, stay home and call your healthcare provider. Older patients and individuals who have severe underlying medical conditions or are immunocompromised should contact their healthcare provider early, even if their illness is mild. If you have severe symptoms, such as persistent pain or pressure in the chest, new confusion or inability to arouse, or bluish lips of face, contact your healthcare provider or emergency room and seek care immediately. Your doctor will determine if you have signs and symptoms of COVID-19 and whether you should be tested.\n", "questionText": "\n\nShould I be tested for COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 2, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 2, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_3": {"answerText": "Using the CDC-developed diagnostic test, a negative result means that the virus that causes COVID-19 was not found in the person’s sample. In the early stages of infection, it is possible the virus will not be detected.\nFor COVID-19, a negative test result for a sample collected while a person has symptoms likely means that the COVID-19 virus is not causing their current illness.\n", "questionText": "\n\nCan a person test negative and later test positive for COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 3, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 3, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "Current symptoms reported for patients with COVID-19 have included mild to severe respiratory illness with fever<a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#footnote1\"><sup>1</sup></a>1, cough, and difficulty breathing. Read about <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/symptoms-testing/symptoms.html\">COVID-19 Symptoms</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat are the symptoms and complications that COVID-19 can cause?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"topic": "Healthcare Professionals and Health Departments", "sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584389929382", "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "For recommendations and guidance on persons under investigation; infection control, including personal protective equipment guidance; home care and isolation; and case investigation, see <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-nCoV/hcp/clinical-criteria.html\">Information for Healthcare Professionals</a>. For information on specimen collection and shipment, see <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-nCoV/lab/index.html\">Information for Laboratories.</a> For information for public health professional on COVID-19, see <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/php/index.html\">Information for Public Health Professionals</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat should healthcare professionals and health departments do?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584390222777", "topic": "COVID-19 and Funerals", "typeOfInfo_4": {"answerText": "When a US citizen dies outside the United States, the deceased person’s next of kin or legal representative should notify US consular officials at the Department of State. Consular personnel are available 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, to provide assistance to US citizens for overseas emergencies. If a family member, domestic partner, or legal representative is in a different country from the deceased person, he or she should call the Department of State’s Office of Overseas Citizens Services in Washington, DC, from 8 am to 5 pm Eastern time, Monday through Friday, at 888-407-4747 (toll-free) or 202-501-4444. For emergency assistance after working hours or on weekends and holidays, call the Department of State switchboard at 202-647-4000 and ask to speak with the Overseas Citizens Services duty officer. In addition, the <a class=\"tp-link-policy\" data-domain-ext=\"gov\" href=\"https://www.usembassy.gov/\">US embassy<span class=\"sr-only\">external icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-external x16 fill-external\"></span></a>external icon closest to or in the country where the US citizen died can provide assistance.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat should I do if my family member died from COVID-19 while overseas?\n\n", "questionID": 4, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 4, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_5": {"answerText": "CDC does not require an autopsy before the remains of a person who died overseas are returned to the United States. Depending on the circumstances surrounding the death, some countries may require an autopsy. Sources of support to the family include the local consulate or embassy, travel insurance provider, tour operator, faith-based and aid organizations, and the deceased’s employer. There likely will need to be an official identification of the body and official documents issued by the consular office.\nCDC requirements for importing human remains depend upon if the body has been embalmed, cremated, or if the person died from a <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/quarantine/aboutlawsregulationsquarantineisolation.html\">quarantinable communicable disease</a>.\nAt this time, COVID-19 is a quarantinable communicable disease in the United States and the remains must meet the standards for importation found in 42 Code of Federal Regulations Part 71.55 and may be cleared, released, and authorized for entry into the United States only under the following conditions:\n\nThe remains are cremated; OR\nThe remains are properly embalmed and placed in a hermetically sealed casket; OR\nThe remains are accompanied by a permit issued by the CDC Director. The CDC permit (if applicable) must accompany the human remains at all times during shipment.\n\nPermits for the importation of the remains of a person known or suspected to have died from a quarantinable communicable disease may be obtained through the CDC Division of Global Migration and Quarantine by calling the CDC Emergency Operations Center at 770-488-7100 or emailing <a href=\"mailto:dgmqpolicyoffice@cdc.gov\">dgmqpolicyoffice@cdc.gov</a>.\n\n\n\nPlease see <a href=\"http://www.cdc.gov/importation/human-remains.html\">CDC’s guidance</a> for additional information.\n", "questionText": "\n\nMy family member died from COVID-19 while overseas. What are the requirements for returning the body to the United States?\n\n", "questionID": 5, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 5, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_2": {"answerText": "COVID-19 is a new disease and we are still learning how it spreads. The virus that causes COVID-19 is thought to mainly spread from close contact (i.e., within about 6 feet) with a person who is currently sick with COVID-19. The virus likely spreads primarily through respiratory droplets produced when an infected person coughs or sneezes, similar to how influenza and other respiratory infections spread. These droplets can land in the mouths or noses of people who are nearby or possibly be inhaled into the lungs. This type of spread is not a concern after death.\nIt may be possible that a person can get COVID-19 by touching a surface or object that has the virus on it and then touching their own mouth, nose, or possibly their eyes, but this is not thought to be the main way the virus spreads.\nPeople should consider not touching the body of someone who has died of COVID-19. Older people and people of all ages with severe underlying health conditions are at higher risk of developing serious COVID-19 illness. There may be less of a chance of the virus spreading from certain types of touching, such as holding the hand or hugging after the body has been prepared for viewing. Other activities, such as kissing, washing, and shrouding should be avoided before, during, and after the body has been prepared, if possible. If washing the body or shrouding are important religious or cultural practices, families are encouraged to work with their community cultural and religious leaders and funeral home staff on how to reduce their exposure as much as possible. At a minimum, people conducting these activities should wear disposable gloves. If splashing of fluids is expected, additional personal protective equipment (PPE) may be required (such as disposable gown, faceshield or goggles and facemask).\nCleaning should be conducted in accordance with manufacturer’s instructions for all cleaning and disinfection products (e.g., concentration, application method and contact time, etc.). <a class=\"tp-link-policy\" data-domain-ext=\"gov\" href=\"https://www.epa.gov/sites/production/files/2020-03/documents/sars-cov-2-list_03-03-2020.pdf\" target=\"new\">Products with EPA-approved emerging viral pathogens claims<span class=\"sr-only\">pdf icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-pdf x16 fill-pdf\"></span><span class=\"file-details\"></span><span class=\"sr-only\">external icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-external x16 fill-external\"></span></a>pdf iconexternal icon are expected to be effective against COVID-19 based on data for harder to kill viruses. After removal of PPE, perform <a href=\"/handwashing/when-how-handwashing.html\">hand hygiene</a> by washing hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds or using an alcohol-based hand sanitizer that contains at least 60% alcohol if soap and water are not available. Soap and water should be used if the hands are visibly soiled.\n", "questionText": "\n\nAm I at risk if I touch someone who died of COVID-19 after they have passed away?\n\n", "questionID": 2, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 2, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_3": {"answerText": "A funeral or visitation service can be held for a person who has died of COVID-19. Funeral home workers should follow their routine infection prevention and control precautions when handling a decedent who died of COVID-19. If it is necessary to transfer a body to a bag, follow <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/infectioncontrol/basics/standard-precautions.html\">Standard Precautions</a>, including additional personal protective equipment (PPE) if splashing of fluids is expected. For transporting a body after the body has been bagged, disinfect the outside of the bag with a <a class=\"tp-link-policy\" data-domain-ext=\"gov\" href=\"https://www.epa.gov/sites/production/files/2020-03/documents/sars-cov-2-list_03-03-2020.pdf\" target=\"new\">product with EPA-approved emerging viral pathogens claims<span class=\"sr-only\">pdf icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-pdf x16 fill-pdf\"></span><span class=\"file-details\"></span><span class=\"sr-only\">external icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-external x16 fill-external\"></span></a>pdf iconexternal icon expected to be effective against COVID-19 based on data for harder to kill viruses. Follow the manufacturer’s instructions for all cleaning and disinfection products (e.g., concentration, application method and contact time, etc.). Wear disposable nitrile gloves when handling the body bag.\nEmbalming can be conducted. During embalming, follow Standard Precautions including the use of additional PPE if splashing is expected (e.g. disposable gown, faceshield or goggles and facemask). Wear appropriate respiratory protection if any procedures will generate aerosols or if required for chemicals used in accordance with the manufacturer’s label. Wear heavy-duty gloves over nitrile disposable gloves if there is a risk of cuts, puncture wounds, or other injuries that break the skin. Additional information on how to safely conduct aerosol-generating procedures is in the <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/guidance-postmortem-specimens.html#autopsy\">CDC’s Postmortem Guidance</a>. Cleaning should be conducted in accordance with manufacturer’s instructions. <a class=\"tp-link-policy\" data-domain-ext=\"gov\" href=\"https://www.epa.gov/sites/production/files/2020-03/documents/sars-cov-2-list_03-03-2020.pdf\" target=\"new\">Products with EPA-approved emerging viral pathogens claims<span class=\"sr-only\">pdf icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-pdf x16 fill-pdf\"></span><span class=\"file-details\"></span><span class=\"sr-only\">external icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-external x16 fill-external\"></span></a>pdf iconexternal icon are expected to be effective against COVID-19 based on data for harder to kill viruses. Follow the manufacturer’s instructions for all cleaning and disinfection products (e.g., concentration, application method and contact time, etc.).\nAfter cleaning and removal of PPE, perform <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/handwashing/when-how-handwashing.html\">hand hygiene</a> by washing hands with soap and water for at least 20 seconds or using an alcohol-based hand sanitizer that contains at least 60% alcohol if soap and water is not available. Soap and water should be used if the hands are visibly soiled.\nDecedents with COVID-19 can be buried or cremated, but check for any additional state and local requirements that may dictate the handling and disposition of the remains of individuals who have died of certain infectious diseases.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat do Funeral Home Workers need to know about handling decedents who had COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 3, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 3, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "There is currently no known risk associated with being in the same room at a funeral or visitation service with the body of someone who died of COVID-19.\n", "questionText": "\n\nAm I at risk if I go to a funeral or visitation service for someone who died of COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"topic": "What CDC is Doing", "sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584390797275", "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "This is an emerging, rapidly evolving situation and CDC will continue to provide updated information as it becomes available. CDC works 24/7 to protect people’s health. More information about <a href=\"/coronavirus/2019-ncov/cases-updates/summary.html#cdc-response\">CDC’s response to COVID-19</a> is available online.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat is CDC doing about COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/faq.html#anchor_1584390773118", "topic": "COVID-19 and Animals", "typeOfInfo_4": {"answerText": "You should restrict contact with pets and other animals while you are sick with COVID-19, just like you would around other people. Although there have not been reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19, it is still recommended that people sick with COVID-19 limit contact with animals until more information is known about the virus. When possible, have another member of your household care for your animals while you are sick. If you are sick with COVID-19, avoid contact with your pet, including petting, snuggling, being kissed or licked, and sharing food. If you must care for your pet or be around animals while you are sick, wash your hands before and after you interact with pets and wear a facemask.\n", "questionText": "\n\nShould I avoid contact with pets or other animals if I am sick with COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 4, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 4, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_5": {"answerText": "Animals imported from China will need to meet <a href=\"/importation/bringing-an-animal-into-the-united-states/index.html\">CDC</a> and <a class=\"tp-link-policy\" data-domain-ext=\"gov\" href=\"https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/ourfocus/animalhealth/animal-and-animal-product-import-information/live-animal-imports/import-live-animals\">USDA<span class=\"sr-only\">external icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-external x16 fill-external\"></span></a>external icon requirements for entering the United States. At this time, there is no evidence that companion animals including pets can spread COVID-19. As with any animal introduced to a new environment, animals recently imported from China should be observed daily for signs of illness. If an animal becomes ill, the animal should be examined by a veterinarian. Call your local veterinary clinic before bringing the animal into the clinic and let them know that the animal was recently in China.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat precautions should be taken for animals that have recently been imported (for example, by shelters, rescue groups, or as personal pets) from China?\n\n", "questionID": 5, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 5, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_2": {"answerText": "Please refer to <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/importation/bringing-an-animal-into-the-united-states/index.html\">CDC’s requirements for bringing a dog to the United States</a>. The current <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/importation/bringing-an-animal-into-the-united-states/rabies-vaccine.html\">requirements for rabies vaccination</a> apply to dogs imported from China, a high-risk country for rabies.\n", "questionText": "\n\nCan I travel to the United States with dogs or import dogs into the United States during the COVID-19 outbreak?\n\n", "questionID": 2, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 2, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_3": {"answerText": "While this virus seems to have emerged from an animal source, it is now spreading from person-to-person in China. There is no reason to think that any animals including pets in the United States might be a source of infection with this new coronavirus. To date, CDC has not received any reports of pets or other animals becoming sick with COVID-19. At this time, there is no evidence that companion animals including pets can spread COVID-19. However, since animals can spread other diseases to people, it’s always a good idea to wash your hands after being around animals. For more information on the many benefits of pet ownership, as well as staying safe and healthy around animals including pets, livestock, and wildlife, visit CDC’s <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/healthypets/index.html\">Healthy Pets, Healthy People website</a>.\n", "questionText": "\n\nShould I be concerned about pets or other animals and COVID-19?\n\n", "questionID": 3, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 3, "isAnnotated": "false"}, "typeOfInfo_1": {"answerText": "CDC does not have any evidence to suggest that imported animals or animal products pose a risk for spreading COVID-19 in the United States. This is a rapidly evolving situation and information will be updated as it becomes available. The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the U. S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), and the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS) play distinct but complementary roles in regulating the importation of live animals and animal products into the United States. <a href=\"https://www.cdc.gov/importation/index.html\">CDC regulates</a> animals and animal products that pose a threat to human health, <a class=\"tp-link-policy\" data-domain-ext=\"gov\" href=\"https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/ourfocus/animalhealth/animal-and-animal-product-import-information/ct_animal_imports_home\">USDA regulates<span class=\"sr-only\">external icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-external x16 fill-external\"></span></a>external icon animals and animal products that pose a threat to agriculture; and <a class=\"tp-link-policy\" data-domain-ext=\"gov\" href=\"https://www.fws.gov/le/businesses.html\">FWS regulates<span class=\"sr-only\">external icon</span><span aria-hidden=\"true\" class=\"fi cdc-icon-external x16 fill-external\"></span></a>external icon importation of endangered species and wildlife that can harm the health and welfare of humans, the interests of agriculture, horticulture, or forestry, and the welfare and survival of wildlife resources.\n", "questionText": "\n\nWhat about imported animals or animal products?\n\n", "questionID": 1, "targetEducationLevel": "", "needUpdate": "", "hasAnswer": "true", "containsURLs": "", "answerID": 1, "isAnnotated": "false"}}
{"sourceName": "CDC", "sourceDate": "March 19, 2020", "dateScraped": 1584651254, "lastUpdateTime": ""}
